ANDREW BOYD

Full Stack Developer

+44 7736 463178

ajb5779@outlook.com

www.ajboyd.co.uk

Belfast, Northern Ireland

A qualified Full Stack Developer with knowledge of a wide range of programming languages and frameworks. Wide-ranging software development experience gained in a relatively short period demonstrating an aptitude for coding and an ability to understand and implement complex concepts on real-world projects.

Strong technical skills are coupled with an IT project management skillset to ensure that work is planned thoroughly and executed to that plan. Strong communication skills, logical thinking and professional experience are demonstrated in the ability to resolve complex issues whilst maintaining and developing working relationships.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Haematology IT Projects Manager

Belfast Health & Social Care Trust | 2016 - Present

Managed hardware/software installations and upgrades within the BHSCT Haematology Laboratories. Acted as System Manager/Subject Matter Expert for several departmental IT systems; involved in the day-to-day management of the systems (implementing changes, troubleshooting issues, liaising with suppliers etc.) Extracted, analysed and presented data (regularly and ad-hoc) for departmental meetings, regulatory bodies and research projects

Quality Officer

Belfast Health & Social Care Trust | 2015 - 2016

Developed and managed the Quality Management System within the Biochemistry Laboratories of the BHSCT.

Managed the document control system, completed audits and investigated departmental incidents. Worked with Senior Management on preparation for audit by regulatory bodies.

Biomedical Scientist

South Eastern Health & Social Care Trust | 2007 - 2015

Manual and automated testing of blood and body fluids

Decision making/authorisation of abnormal results and communication of such results to relevant personnel

PROJECTS

espressOrders

Full Stack Frameworks Project (Code Institute)

An e-commerce application, built with Python/Django, which allows users to order and pay for drinks from coffee carts.

Features: Stripe Payment Integration, AWS (S3 & IAMS), BootStrap

Campfire Cooking

Data Centric Project (Code Institute)

A recipe sharing site, built with Python/Flask, which allows users to add, edit and share their favourite recipes.

Features: Materialize, jQuery, MongoDB, Heroku

Craft Gins NI

Interactive Frontend Project (Code Institute)

An interactive website, built with JavaScript/HTML/CSS, which gives users information on craft gins producers in Northern Ireland and where best to sample their products.

Features: API Manipulation, BootStrap, jQuery

SKILLS

Technical

Python/Django/Flask

JavaScript/jQuery

HTML/CSS

Postgres SQL/MongoDB

AWS (S3/IAMS)

Bootstrap/Materialize

Stripe Payment

Professional

Logical Thinker

Strong problem Solver

Project Manager

Effective Communication

EDUCATION

Dip Full Stack Web Development

Code Institute, Dublin 2020 - 2021

MSc Toxicology

University of Surrey 2004 - 2005

BSc Applied Biochemical Science

University of Ulster 1997 - 2001

INTERESTS

Learning Jazz Piano

Swimming

Running/Parkrun



